Guide to the Records of the Office of the President (Dr. James McNaughton Hester) RG.3.0.7
New York University Archives
- Series XII: Student Affairs Series, 1962-1975 (Boxes 70-79)
  Box 5 contains an exchange between the alumni and the University over the decision to discontinue intercollegiate basketball and diminish encouragement of track because of financial difficulties. This box also contains a dispute over scholarship aid and placement of Puerto Rican students in the Graduate School of Social Work. Also of interest is a folder on the Students for a Democratic Society, which contains posters and bulletins circulated by the organization and the administration response.
  Folder names followed by an asterisk (*) contain materials of a sensitive nature. Researchers must consult with the archivists before being granted access.
  - Admissions, Ed Dev & Community Enrollment Plan, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Admissions, Tuition, 1965-1968 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Admissions, Tuition, 1969-1972 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Admissions, Tuition, 1972-1975 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - African American Teachers Forum, 1967 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Afro-American Student Center: Hatchett dismissed, 1962-1967 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Hatchett, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Hatchett, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Hatchett, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Hatchett, 1969-1971 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Hatchett letters, from alumni protesting, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Hatchett letters, re internal memo A-B, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Hatchett, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - F, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - G, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - H-J, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - K, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - L, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - M, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - N-R, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Sa-Sm, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - So-Sw, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - T-Z, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - AASC:Letters regarding hiring, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Letters regarding hiring, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Jewish Groups, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Letters to from others re hiring, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Hatchett, Press Clippings, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Hatchett, Press Releases, 1968 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Transcript of Oct 1968 Speech (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Letters supporting Firing, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - A-F, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - G-K, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - L-N, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - O-Sp, 1968 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - St-V, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - W-Z, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Letters from Outside People, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Letters regarding Firing, not answd., 1968 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Form Letters, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Alumni & Benefactors meetings, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Letter, never sent, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence w black students, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Dismissal, Faculty reaction, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Dismissal Letters, no return addrs., 1968 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence w black students, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Afro-American Student Center, Hatchett Faculty Groups Reaction, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Letters, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence w Arthur Goldberg, 1968-1969 (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Letter to Police Comm, Howard Leary, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Letters w form response A-H, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - I-Z, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Student Reactions, Petitions, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Athletics, 1971 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Athletics Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Financial Aid Scholarships, 1970-1971 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - General, 1971-1972 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Hayden Hall, Constitution Policy, 1974-1975 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Quality of Student Life Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - ROTC, 1972-1975 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - Student Conduct, 1968-1969 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Student Conduct, 1969-1970 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Campus Unrest, 1968-1969 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Campus Unrest, 1969-1970 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Campus Unrest, 1970-1972 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - April and May events, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Book Store Sit-in, 1967 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Chi Reston Disruption *, 1968-1969 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - JMH Statements, 1968-1969 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Kirkman *, 1968-1969 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Mason *, 1968-1969 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Political Forum, 1968-1969 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Public Reaction, 1968-1969 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Williamson *, 1969 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Comments on JMH 9/4 letter, 1970 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Disruption Booklet, 1970 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Greene-Byrnes Incident, 1969 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Hatchatt Affair, 1967-1968 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Loeb Lecture Incident, 1967 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - May Events 1970 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - May Events A-F, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - F-I, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - J-R, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - S-Z, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Anonymous, and CCC, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Schools & Departments, 1970 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Strike Committee & etc., 1970 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Tuition refund to Paynter, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Material for JMH, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Protests, 1968-1970 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Public Response, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - ROTC Disruption, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Vanderbilt Hall Sit-in, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Weinstein Sub Cellar evacuation, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Student Conduct, Columbia University Protest, 1968-1970 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Disciplinary Proceedings, 1969-1973 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Drugs, 1969-1972 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Moratorium, 1969 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Politics, 1967-1971 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Politics, memo of Sept. 4, 1970 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Students for a Democratic Society, 1968-1971 (Box 79, Folder 3)
- Series XIII: Interviews, Speeches, and Testimony, 1962-1975 (Boxes 80-87, 92)
  - List of Speeches (to 1971), 1970 September 23 (Box 83, Folder 33)
  - List of Speeches (1968-1970), 1968 April-1970 November (Box 82, Folder 31)
  - List of Speeches (1969-1972), circa 1972 (Box 83, Folder 34)
  - Downtown Brooklyn Association, "The Cultural Future of Brooklyn", 1962 January 22 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Girls Clubs of America, "Women of Tomorrow", 1962 March 26 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - National Council of Administrative Women in Education, "Women of Tomorrow" (Revised) [May 9, 1962], 1962 May 9 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Greater New York Council for Foreign Students, Inc. [May 24, 1962], 1962 May 21-24 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Radio Voice of America, "For Algerian Independence Day" (French) [June 1962], 1962 June (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Village Independent Democrats Annual Dinner, "The Community and its University" [June 7, 1962], 1962 May 1-June 14 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Radio Liberty Taping [September 13, 1962], 1961 December 16-1962 September 14 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Radio Voice of America, Japan Program [September 14, 1962], 1962 September 6-30 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - New York University Freshman Convocations [September 17-18, 1962], 1962 May 25-September 28 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - New York State Association of School Superintendents, "Education for the Demands of Our Time" [September 25, 1962], 1962 September 25 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - New York State Association of School Superintendents, "Education for the Demands of Our Time" [September 25, 1962], 1959-October 1962 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Trinity Church, Service for the Blessing of God Upon the Courts of Justice [October 10, 1962], 1962 July 26-October 31 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - New York University Inauguration [October 25, 1962]: Address and Proceedings, 1962 October 25 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - New York University Inauguration [October 25, 1962], 1961 November-1962 October (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Greenwich Village Chamber of Commerce, Man of the Year Award [November 1, 1962], 1962 November 1-13 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Institution on Federal Taxation of New York University, "The Private University in Our Tax Economy", 1962 November 13 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Institution on Federal Taxation of New York University, "The Private University in Our Tax Economy" [November 13, 1962], 1962 March 29-November 13 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - British Schools and Universities Club of New York Annual Dinner [November 14, 1962], 1962 November 14-December 3 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Colony Club, "The Modern Woman and the Urban University" [November 20, 1962], 1962 May 31-November 20 (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Eastern College Athletic Conference, 1962 December 13 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Andiron Club, "Implications of International Interdependence" [December 21, 1962], 1962 December 10, 21 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Council on Social Work Education, "The Impact of Our Changing Values on Education" [January 23, 1963], 1963 January 23 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Council on Social Work Education, "The Impact of our Changing Values on Education" [January 23, 1963], 1962 September 10-1963 March 27 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - American Association of University Women, "The Increasing Pace of Higher Education" [February 2, 1963], 1963 January 18, February 2 (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - Eastern Association of College and University Business Officers [February 25, 1963], 1963 January 24, February 24 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - New-York Historical Society, "New York University and New York City" [March 5, 1963], 1963 March 5 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - New-York Historical Society, "New York University and New York City" [March 5, 1963], 1963 February 21-March 6 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Greensboro College, "Changing Demands in the Preparation of Students", 1963 March 7 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Greensboro College, "The Responsibilities of Private Higher Education in America" [March 6, 1963] and "Changing Demands in the Preparation of Students" [March 7, 1963], 1962 November 16- 1963 March 7 (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - Daily News, Response to "Inquiring Reporter", 1963 April 3 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Time Magazine Article, Memorandum asking Student Publications to Discard Images of Hester Smoking Cigarettes, 1963 June 18-28 (Box 88, Folder 22)
  - International House, Speech to Foreign Students [September 1963], 1963 September 11-October 1 (Box 88, Folder 23)
  - Society of Colonial Wars, 66th Annual Banquet [November 6, 1963], 1963 September 30-November 8 (Box 88, Folder 24)
  - Institute of International Education Regional Conference (New Orleans, LA) [November 11, 1963], 1963 August 30-November 11 (Box 88, Folder 25)
  - Westchester Council of Social Agencies, Inc., 1963 November 19 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Westchester Council of Social Agencies, Inc. [November 19, 1963], 1963 May 10-November 19 (Box 88, Folder 26)
  - "Message for the NYU Notebook" [November 22, 1963], 1961 December-1963 November (Box 88, Folder 27)
  - Statement on the Death of President John F. Kennedy, 1963 November 22 (Box 88, Folder 28)
  - Princeton University Career Panel, "Teaching and Educational Administration" [December 6, 1963], 1963 October 30-December 13 (Box 88, Folder 29)
  - Princeton University Chapel, Sermon [December 22, 1963], 1963 February 28-1964 March 31 (Box 88, Folder 30)
  - Brick Presbyterian Church [January 7, 1964], 1963 August 7,1964 January 7 (Box 88, Folder 31)
  - American Institute of Banking, New York Chapter, Annual Banquet [February 1, 1964], 1964 January 16-February 6 (Box 88, Folder 32)
  - Bronx County Dental Society, 50th Anniversary Greetings, 1964 February 3-March 5 (Box 88, Folder 33)
  - Conference on Nuclear Energy, Public Policy, and the Law: Draft Statement, 1964 February 4 (Box 88, Folder 34)
  - Long Island University, Charter Day [February 5, 1964], 1964 February 5 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Long Island University, Charter Day [February 5, 1964], 1964 February 5-March 27 (Box 88, Folder 35)
  - Report to Faculty and Staff, "Plans for the Decade Ahead, 1964-1973", 1964 March (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Grace Church School Parents' Association Open House [March 1964], 1963 July 23-1964 March 7 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - St. Francis College, Charter Day Convocation (copy), 1964 May 8 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - St. Francis College, Charter Day Convocation, "Education as a Profession" [May 8, 1964], 1964 May 8 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - National Industrial Conference Board, "Federal Subsidy of Higher Education: The Threat and Promise" (copy), 1964 May 22 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - National Industrial Conference Board, "Federal Subsidy of Higher Education: The Threat and Promise" [May 22, 1964], 1964 May 21-22 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Hartwick College Commencement, "What to Believe In" (copy), 1964 May 31 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Hartwick College Commencement, "What to Believe In" [May 31, 1964], 1964 May 20, 31 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Report to Faculty and Staff, "Plans for the Decade Ahead, 1964-1973", 1964 June (Box 80, Folder 1964 June)
  - The Sportsmanship Brotherhood, "The Valuable Heritage of Sportsmanship" [June 4, 1964], 1964 June 4-8 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - New York University Freshman Convocation [Fall 1964], circa 1964 Fall (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - New York Life Insurance Company, Presidents' Council, "The Human Challenge" [September 2, 1964], 1964 May 29-1965 March 8 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - New York Life Insurance Company, Presidents' Council, "The Human Challenge" (copy), 1964 September 2 (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - New York University Parents' Convocation [September 19 and 23, 1964], 1964 September 19, 23 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Friends Seminary, New Building Dedication (copy), 1964 September 22 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Friends Seminary, New Building Dedication [September 22, 1964], 1964 September 18-28 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Bronx County Golden Jubilee Day [October 6, 1964], 1964 October 5-6 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Institute of International Education, Corporate Dinner [October 8, 1964], 1964 September 29, October 8 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Institute of International Education, Corporate Dinner (copy), 1964 October 8 (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Union Junior College, Founders Day Convocation [October 16, 1964], 1964 May 14-October 16 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Union Junior College, Founders Day Convocation (copy), 1964 October 16 (Box 80, Folder 20)
  - Alumni Fund Rally [October 19, 1964], 1964 October 9-19 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - International Nickel Metallurgical Research Laboratories Dedication [October 29, 1964], 1964 October 12, 29 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - International Nickel Metallurgical Research Laboratories Dedication (copy), 1964 October 29 (Box 80, Folder 21)
  - Lafayette College, Founders Day Convocation [October 31, 1964], 1964 October 31-November 4 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Collegiate School, Fourth Century Fund Dinner [November 16, 1964], 1964 September 26, November 16 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Notes for Speech to University Heights Alumni [November 18, 1964], circa 1964 November 18 (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Gallatin Dinner [December 10, 1964], 1964 December 10 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Dinner Honoring Professor Abraham I. Katsh [January 13, 1965], 1965 January 8-15 (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - New York University Guggenheim School of Aeronautics, Dinner Honoring William T. Schwendler [January 26, 1965], 1965 January 26-February 12 (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - Institute of International Education, Diamond Ball [January 27, 1965], 1965 January 25, 27 (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - Policy Speech, "Today's Challenge and Tomorrow's Mission" (draft), circa 1965 January 28 (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - Policy Speech, "Today's Challenge and Tomorrow's Mission" (copy of draft), 1965 January 28 (Box 80, Folder 22)
  - University Club, Centennial Dinner [February 4, 1965], 1964 September 2-1965 February 18 (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - University Club, Centennial Dinner (copy), 1965 February 4 (Box 80, Folder 23)
  - New York University School of Education, 75th Anniversary Dinner [March 1, 1965], 1964 May 1-1965 March 1 (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - Society of Foreign Consuls Luncheon [March 9, 1965], 1964 November 12-1965 March 9 (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - Weaver Hall Dedication [March 29, 1965], 1965 January 29-March 29 (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - College of Dentistry Centennial [April 2, 1965], 1965 April 21 (Box 89, Folder 27)
  - Boni Dinner [April 7, 1965], 1964 November 25-1965 April 7 (Box 89, Folder 28)
  - Boni Dinner (copy), 1965 April 7 (Box 80, Folder 24)
  - Dorothy Gordon Youth Forum Appearance [May 7, 1965], circa 1965 April 12-May 23 (Box 89, Folder 31)
  - Graduate School of Public Administration Awards Dinner [May 13, 1965], 1965 April 27-May 13 (Box 89, Folder 29)
  - State University of New York, Inauguration of Samuel B. Gould, 1965 May (Box 80, Folder 25)
  - State University of New York, Inauguration of Samuel B. Gould [May 13, 1965], 1965 April 2-May 13 (Box 89, Folder 30)
  - Center for International Studies Inaugural Dinner [May 24, 1965], 1965 May 24-26 (Box 89, Folder 32)
  - Conference on Social Growth and Democracy in Turkey [May 27, 1965], 1965 February 7-May 27 (Box 89, Folder 33)
  - Alfred University Commencement, "Who Are You?", 1965 June 6 (Box 80, Folder 26)
  - Alfred University Commencement, "Who Are You?" [June 6, 1965], 1965 June 6-15 (Box 89, Folder 34)
  - New York University Commencement, "The Generation of Hope", 1965 June 9 (Box 80, Folder 27)
  - New York University Commencement, "The Generation of Hope" [June 9, 1965], 1965 June 9-1966 April 28 (Box 89, Folder 35)
  - International Students, 1965 September 17 (Box 80, Folder 28)
  - Conference of the International Council of Museums, "The Urban University and the Museum of Art", 1965 September 29 (Box 80, Folder 29)
  - Radio-tape Session on Dean Paul A. McGhee, 1965 October 12 (Box 80, Folder 30)
  - Conference on Scientific and Technical Information on Industry, 1965 October 14 (Box 80, Folder 31)
  - National Academy of Engineering, "Engineering and the University", 1965 October 21 (Box 80, Folder 32)
  - Testimony Before the Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education, "Proposal for a Mixed Economy to Meet Higher Education Needs in New York State, 1965 November (Box 80, Folder 33)
  - Empire State Chamber of Commerce Conference on Higher Education, 1965 December 1 (Box 80, Folder 34)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1965 December 9 (Box 80, Folder 35)
  - Television Statement, 1965 December 15 (Box 80, Folder 36)
  - Medical Center 125th Anniversary Dinner, 1966 February 2 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Los Angeles Alumni Meeting, "The University and the Urban Challenge" (Excerpt), 1966 February 11 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - San Francisco Planning and Urban Renewal Association "The City and the University", 1966 February 14 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - New York City Board of Education Conference of Superintendents, "The Urban University and the Humanities", 1966 February 24 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - New York University School of Education Diamond Jubilee, 1966 March 12 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - National Conference on Higher Education, "Urbanization and Higher Education", 1966 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - State of the University (Education and Law Alumni), 1966 March 26, 1966 March 29 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - National Conference on the Large-Scale Public Electronic Data Processing System, 1966 April 1 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - New York Chamber of Commerce, "The Future Economy of Higher Education in New York City", 1966 April 5 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Eastern Business Teachers Association, "Education for the Changing World", 1966 April 7 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Hofstra College, "The University and the Individual", 1966 April 15 (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - Sylvanus Thayer Installation, 1966 May 15 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - New York University Commencement, 1966 June 5 (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Cornell University Medical School Commencement, "Tomorrow's Medical Leadership", 1966 June 8 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Cleveland State University, "The New Responsibility of the Urban University", 1966 June 13 (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - Los Angeles Town Hall, "The Urban University and the Central City", 1966 July 12 (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - Church of the Ascension (New York, NY), "Religion and the Purposes of the University", 1966 October 16 (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - Saint Andrew's Society, "The Land We Live In", 1966 November 30 (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Executive Reorganization, "Federal Role in Urban Problems", 1966 December 2 (Box 81, Folder 19)
  - Student Radio Interview, "The University in the 21st Century", 1967 February 9 (Box 81, Folder 20)
  - Morehouse College Centennial, 1967 February 18 (Box 81, Folder 21)
  - "Our Public School Heritage" (Long Beach, CA), 1967 April 28 (Box 81, Folder 22)
  - Virginia State College Commencement, "The Obligations of College Graduates", 1967 May 30 (Box 81, Folder 23)
  - New York University Baccalaureate Address, 1967 June 11 (Box 81, Folder 24)
  - New York University Commencement, 1967 June 13 (Box 81, Folder 25)
  - Bronx Community College Commencement, 1967 June 15 (Box 81, Folder 26)
  - WCBS Radio Statement, 1967 July 11 (Box 81, Folder 27)
  - New York University Presidential Convocations for New Students, "Personal Honor", 1967 September (Box 81, Folder 28)
  - New York Times Article, "NYU is Upgrading its Academic Requirements", 1967 October 15 (Box 81, Folder 29)
  - Fifth Avenue Association, "Private Higher Education and the Future of New York City", 1967 October 19 (Box 81, Folder 30)
  - Dr. Frederick Loewe Convocation, "The University and the Performing Arts", 1967 October 24 (Box 81, Folder 31)
  - General Theological Seminary 150th Anniversary, "What Do We Ask of Religion?", 1967 November 8 (Box 81, Folder 32)
  - Statement on Japan, 1967 November 9 (Box 81, Folder 33)
  - The Brotherhood Synagogue 30th Anniversary, "Tensions Between the Generations", 1967 November 10 (Box 81, Folder 34)
  - Special Convocation in Honor of His Excellency Eisaku Sato, Prime Minister of Japan, 1967 November 17 (Box 81, Folder 35)
  - Statement on Dow Chemical Company Recruiting Visit, Handout on Procedure for Demonstrators, 1967 November 28 (Box 81, Folder 36)
  - Saint Nicholas Society Dinner, 1967 December 6 (Box 81, Folder 37)
  - Statement on Jos Herzberg, 1967 December 8 (Box 81, Folder 38)
  - "Dormitories at Washington Square College of Arts and Sciences", 1968 February (Box 81, Folder 39)
  - Princeton University, "Ends and Means", 1968 April 19 (Box 81, Folder 40)
  - New York Academy of Public Education, 1968 May 7 (Box 81, Folder 41)
  - Bronx Rotary Luncheon, 1968 May 7 (Box 81, Folder 42)
  - New York University Commencement, "Society's Best Instrument for Change", 1968 June 12 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Institute for the Crippled and Disabled, Institute Day Exercises, 1968 June 18 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Report, "The University and the Disadvantaged", 1968 August (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - "The University and the City" (Rio de Janeiro, Brazil), 1968 August 28 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - New York University Faculty Meeting, 1968 Fall (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - "The Governance of New York University", 1968 September (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - New York University School of Education Faculty Meeting, 1968 September 11 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Presidential Convocations for Freshman and Transfer Students, 1968 September 16 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - New York University Parents Convocation, 1968 September 18 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Community Planning Board Number 2 (SoHo) Statements, 1968 October-1970 October (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Investment Bankers Association of America, New York Group, "Pressures on the Urban University Today", 1968 October 3 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Regional Plan Association, "Interaction Between the University and the Inner City", 1968 November 19 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1968 December 2 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1968 December 4 (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Radio Interview, WOR-AM New York, 1969 January 14 (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Association of the Bar of the City of New York, "Who Should Run the University?", 1969 February 13 (Box 82, Folder 16)